Obyed Ullah Khan

Contact No: +1 (309) 350-9015

Email: obyed.oss@gmail.com | Skype: shoeb.khan842 Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/obyed-ullah-khan/

GitHub: https://github.com/ouks-bd

Mailing Address: 43-15 69st woodside 11377 New-York

Objective

Critical thinker with excellent communication and interpersonal skills and developing automation scripts and executing all levels of testing and coming with time management skills although expertise in manual and automated testing techniques and offering Knowledge of automation testing with selenium and bug trackings tools such as Jira, Trello and familiarity with test processes and agile development methodologies.

Education

Masters in Information Systems Technology (MS-IST) | Auguest, 2023 - Running

Dept. of Information Technology

Wilmington University.

Masters in Computer Science | November, 2018 - November, 2019

Dept. of Computer Science

Jahangirnagar University

Bachelor in Computer Science | June, 2013 - November 2017

Dept. of Computer Science

South East University

Work Experience

D-Bug Station Limited

Senior Software Quality Engineer | July,2023 - Present (Remote)

Prepar	ed automa	ation framewo	rk and test	scripts for we	b applications	in Java l	Jsing Sel	lenium
Webdrive	er, TestNG,	and Extent re	port, Althou	ugh In Cypres	ss Using JavaS	Script.		

☐ Conducting manual testing of software products and ensuring that they meet the defined requirements and user needs.

☐ Perform SQL script to extract data from the database and match ,data with the application, functional requirements and design specifications, and documenting problems, software defects, and test defects.
Brac IT Services Limited (Managed Service -Brac Bank Ltd.)
Software Quality Engineer Augest,2022 – June,2023
☐ Performed different types of testing like Smoke, Sanity, Regression, Integration, Usability, User acceptance, and Compatibility testing on development, staging, and production environment.
☐ Assisting in the creation of automated test scripts using tools such as Selenium or Cypress.
☐ Worked hand in hand with developers and Business Analysts for ensuring better quality.
Beacon Tech LTD.
SQA Engineer 2019 - 15th Auguest 2022
☐ Executed test cases and prepared status reports using the TestRail Test Case Management

Automation Testing Skills:

Software.

UI Testing: Selenium, Appium (Basic).

☐ Testing application: POS, CRM, HRM.

API Testing: Rest Assured, Postman, Newman.

Load Testing: JMeter, Blazemeter. **Testing Frameworks**: TestNG, JUnit.

Reporting Tools: Allure, Testrail.

Other Technical Skills:

Development Platform: IntelliJ, Pycharm, VS Code. **Programming Language**:Java, Javascript, Python.

Database Language: SQL, MySQL. **Source Control**: Github, Gitlab.

Project Management Tools: Trello, Jira.